<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>This is for any of that generation that are looking for the Kingdome [-] with their own observations, but desernes not the signes of the coming [of the?] Son of Man. And especially for them that meet to worship in the old Mass-[house?] in Aldermanbury.</title>
            <author>R. T. (Rebecca Travers), 1609-1688.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1659</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 7 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A94804</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing T2064</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R229356</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">47683505</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 47683505</idno>
            <idno type="VID">172964</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A94804)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 172964)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 2659:18)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>This is for any of that generation that are looking for the Kingdome [-] with their own observations, but desernes not the signes of the coming [of the?] Son of Man. And especially for them that meet to worship in the old Mass-[house?] in Aldermanbury.</title>
                  <author>R. T. (Rebecca Travers), 1609-1688.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for Mary Westwood,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[S.l.] :</pubPlace>
                  <date>in the 11th month. 1659.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Signed at end: R.T.</note>
                  <note>Imperfect: torn, stained, and tightly bound, with loss of text; bracketed words in title conjectured by cataloger.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: Friends' Library (London, England).</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Society of Friends --  Pastoral letters and charges.</term>
               <term>Admonitions --  Quaker authors --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  England --  London --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-06</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2007-06</date>
            <label>Aptara</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>John Latta</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>John Latta</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="treatise">
            <pb facs="tcp:172964:1"/>
            <head>This is for any of that generation that are looking for the Kingdome
with their own obſervations, but deſernes not the ſignes of the coming
Son of Man. And eſpecially for them that meet to worſhip in the old Maſs
in Aldermanbury.</head>
            <p>DArkneſſe hath covered the earth, and groſſe darkneſſe the people, ſo you cannot ſee nor perceive his workin<gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
that is come to overturn the proud, and confound the wiſe and thongh your eares be not bored to be<gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
his voyce, nor your eyes opened to ſee the ſigns that have been in the midſt of you, but are deſpiſing and wandrin<gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
               <gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>ut of the feare, out of the dread of the living God whom we ſerve, and know to be angry with the wicked every
day, and your offerings ſtink before him, and your prayers are an abomination unto him, whoſe flight ſhall come
upon you in the Winter, and on the Sabaoth day: A horrible tempeſt is round about him, and a devouring fire
goes before him, who will plead with all the earth in righteouſneſſe, and will teare in peices thoſe that forget him:
are not you without the remembrance of him? Who have deſpiſed his Meſſengers evilly intreated, and caſt in<gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
ſon, him who in obedience to the maker of heaven, and earth, was ſent among you, as a ſigne unto you, of your
poor, naked, leane, ſtarved ſoules, of your filthy uncleane coverings and righteouſneſſe and the dung of your ſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lemne
aſſemblys which as excrements hath an ill ſavour, and as a menſtrus clo<gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>th, before him who is juſt, and
will not acquit the guilty: for the woe is gone forth even againſt all that are covered, and not with my Spirit,
ſaith the Lord, which ſpirit reproves you of your ſin, of your righteouſneſſe, and your judgements, which are all
out of the truth, falſe and wicked, and you not beleiving, nor obeying that which reproves you wax worſe and
worſe, ſpeaking evill of things you know not, calling good, evill, and evill, good, c<gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>ndemning Gods works juſtify<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing
your own works, puniſhing the innocent and acquitting the guilty: is not this your ſtate? That are in the
practiſes of pride, wantonneſſe, covetouſneſſe, licentious, feaſting, rioting, and ſporting, and then in your vain
minds, and words, in which you can doe nothing elſe but ſin, you ſay it is ſin and wickedneſſe, for any to appeare
before you without cloathing, naked as they were brought into the world, but where will you prove that ſuch have
broken any Law of God: but you that are in the immaginations, which are vain and greive the Lord God <gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
fully ſay that it is wickedneſſe to work on the firſt day of the week; though it be written ſix days ſhalt thou wo<gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
yet are not you aſhamed to perſecute and caſt in priſon, thoſe that love the commands of God, and for the perf<gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mance
thereof are ſufferers by your unrighteous Laws, for as ever it was ſo it is they t<gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>at ſlay the holy one and the<gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
break the commands of God, and are zealous for the traditions of men, O ye Sellers and Buyers of the Scriptur<gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
would not you have judged Iſaiah if he ſhould have gone three years naked in your Citty, as you may read h<gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
Iſaiah the 20. the 2. and the 3. verſe. And would not this generation have accounted Ezekiel, if they had <gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
in his days as mad as the Quakers, if they had ſeen him bake his bread with dung, and ſhave his head <gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
beard, and burn part of the hair, and throw part in the wind, as is written in the 4. chap. of Ezekiel the 12.
and the 15. Ezekiel the 5. 6. 3. and 4. verſes. Surely the Scriptures wherein you truſt doth condemne you, and
ſhall one pay witneſſe againſt you, and then in vain may you cry for Hills, and Mountaines to fall, and hide you
from the preſence of the lambe, whoſe comming is at hand, who is this day deviding the ſheepe from the Goats
and gathering his elect into the arme of his power the defence of the righteous, and will breake to peices all the
ungodly, which have a name to live but are dead: but the Trumpet is ſounded, and the Alarm is heard, and the
dead ſhall ariſe and come to judgement before the Lamb: where will you hide who hate to be reformed and profeſſing
will not cover you, Chriſts, nor the Apoſtles words, will not ſave you: all the workers of iniquity muſt depart, the
lake is prepared, the Kingdome of darkneſſe is fitted for all that hate the light, and when you are ſtripped, and
ſet naked, all your glory ſtained, haughtyneſſe debaſed, then ſhall you know that it was in the long-ſuffering, and
everlaſting mercy of God, that you have been viſited, and warned by dreadfull words, and ſignes, that you might
have ſeaſed from provoking him, that we know aſſuredly can deliver from all your cruell oppreſſing, and whether 
he will doe it ſudingly or no, we are not carefull: for we have his preſence who makes rich in want, and gives 
peace and joy in all our ſufferings, yea, that paſſes your underſtanding, and the aſſured hope of our reward, is
ſure, and ſtedfaſt, fixed in God whoſe works are wrought, in, and by them, who into his will are gathered, out of
mans will which cannot work Gods righteouſneſſe: but this is a miſtery to you who are eſtabliſhing your own righte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ouſneſſe,
which will ſudingly, and horribly come to an end, for our ſalvation is nigh, and our deliverance near
and in what appearance ſoever we are ſent unto you, our teſtimony is true, for it is againſt all unrighteouſs <gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
practiſes, and worſhips, which God is caſting downe, even he that is come to finiſh ſin, and to put an end to t<gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
greſſion, and to bring in everlaſting righteouſneſſe, and his power, and kingdome which ſhall never have <gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
felt and known, among the deſpiſed Quakers, and this is from one of them that long and much followed, <gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
places you call your Churches, and them you call your teachers, and never left them till I ſaw God was de<gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
from them: for while Joſeph was in Egypt, there was ſome food for Jacobs ſeed, but he not there the ſeed <gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
preſſed, for the deliverance of which the Lord is riſen, and the oppreſſors ſhall be tormented, and thou<gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
beleive not, yet when he that will come, ſhall come to take vengance on you for their wrongs, who have a<gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
ſuffer for the teſtimony of a pure conſcience, you ſhall confeſſe unto him whoſe ways are righteous, and whoſe j<gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
ments are paſt finding out, by the diſobedient, but ſhall be felt by the diſpiſes thereof; that loves darkneſſe <gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
then light, and of this you have been warned, and now are by me that pittyes all your ſoules that lyes in Ca<gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
under the bondage of Corruption.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>R. T.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>Printed for Mary Weſtwood in the 11th month. 1659.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
